Will Epperson

I'm a Ph.D. student in the HCII at CMU advised by Dominik Moritz and Adam Perer.

My research interests lie in **developing ways to make complex systems easier to use and understand for experts and non-experts.** I am interested in how we can build tools to help users interact with their data through understandable Machine Learning, interactive visualizations, and reccomended analysis. I'm also interested in how these techniques can be applied to the medical domain to improve both doctor and patient experiences.





Education

August 2020 - Present

Ph.D. in Human Computer Interaction

Carnegie Mellon University

Advisors: Dominik Moritz, Adam Perer

Sample Coursework: Computational Medicine

August 2016 - May 2020

B.S. in Computer Science

Georgia Institute of Technology

GPA: 4.0, Summa Cum Laude, threads in Intelligence and Modeling/Simulation Sample Coursework: Machine Learning, Deep Learning, Computer Vision, Computer Architecture, Algorithms, Computer Simulation, Information Visualization

Publications

FairVis: Visual Analytics for Discovering Intersectional Bias in Machine Learning

Angel Cabrera, Will Epperson, Fred Hohman, Minsuk Kahng, Jamie Morgenstern, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

IEEE Conference on Visual Analytics Science and Technology (VAST). Vancouver, Canada, 2019.

 Project
 Demo
 PDF
 ■ Blog
 ■ Recording
 ■ Slides
 Code
 ■ BibTeX

RECAST: Interactive Auditing of Automatic Toxicity Detection Models

Austin P. Wright, Omar Shaikh, Haekyu Park, Will Epperson, Muhammed Ahmed, Stephane Pinel, Diyi Yang, Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

The eighth International Workshop of Chinese CHI. 2020.

Talks

FairVis

May 2019

IEEE Visualization Conference

Honors and Awards

Stamps President's Scholarship

Full ride scholarship given to 40 incoming freshman at Georgia Tech

Research Experience

January 2019 - May 2020

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

Undergraduate Researcher, Polo Club of Data Science

Advisor: Duen Horng (Polo) Chau

Member of the Polo Club of Data Science working on novel data visulizations to find fairness

issues in Machine Learning models Relevant Skills: Python, Javascript

January 2018 - May 2019

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

Undergraduate Researcher, Automated Algorithm Design

Advisor: Jason Zutty, Greg Rohling

Worked on EMADE algorithm design engine to implement sentiment analysis pipeline to analyze news articles to aid in predicting stock price movements using genetic algorithms. Led project to visualize the genetic algorithm evolution process.

Relevant Skills: Python, Javascript

Industry Experience

Summer 2019

Point72 Asset Management, New York, NY *Data Analytics Intern, Market Intelligence Group*

Mentor: Trevor Rempel

Worked as Data Scientist in alternative data space to clean, model, and understand large

Relevant Skills: Python, Distributed Computing in Spark

Summer 2018

Ultimate Software, Weston, FL

Software Development Intern, Innovation Strategies Team

Mentor: Joseph Cutrono

Designed and developed Slack app to integrate with the UltiPro HR management tool. App published to Slack app store.

Relevant Skills: Typescript, REST API development

Summer 2015

The Home Depot, Atlanta, GA

Software Development Intern

Developed web app for tracking candidate progress throughout hiring process for internal HR

Relevant Skills: Java, HTML/CSS/Javascript

Teaching

August 2017 - December 2018

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, GA

Intro to Database Systems (CS 4400), Instructor: Monica Sweat Designed projects, held office hours and graded for relational databases class.

Leadership & Activities

January 2019 - May 2020

Serve as official representative of the Institute at events/tours for alumni, prospective students, and special guests.

January 2018 - May 2019

Executive Board Member -- Threads Co-chair

Stamps Scholars National Convention 2019

Executive board member of Stamps Scholars National Convention, a 3-day conference with over 700 student attendees. Responsible for 20-person committee that plans and coordinates the different content threads of the convention.

Sample Projects

December 2018

ICLR'19 Reproducibility Challenge

Implemented the architecture and reproduced results for an ICLR'19 submission using GANs to decorrelate sensitive data, titled Generative Adversarial Models for Learning Private and Fair Representations.

January 2018 - December 2018

Atlanta Crime Map

Led a team as part of Data Science Club at GT to analyze and visualize crime data on and around GT's campus to provide insight into crime frequency and details for GTPD.

February 2018

Citadel Datathon

Created supervised learning system to predict dangerous road areas to help make cities safer at Citadel and Correlation One's Datathon at Georgia Tech. Team placed top 3.

February 2017 - December 2017

RECONSO Research

Developed interface between core state machine and battery systems on Avionics team of student-led cube satellite project. Learned C while working on project.

Skills

Programing Languages: Python (Advanced), Javascript/Typescript (Intermediate), HTML (Intermediate), SQL (Intermediate), Java (Intermediate), C (Basic)

Toolkits, Frameworks, Software: Pytorch, Scikit-learn, Git, VegaLite, D3, Tableau,

MacOS, Windows, Linux

Natural Languages: English (Native), Spanish (Advanced)